thebreakdown.xyz 2019-07-22

# Privacy Policy - TheBreakdown.xyz

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://thebreakdown.xyz.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact forms

When contacting us through our contact form, your name, email address, and message, and IP address are collected. This information is used to help us identify you when responding to your message. All messages are stored locally in WordPress and emailed to us at Hello@TheBreakdown.xyz. These messages are kept indefinitely in order to better serve you if you reach out again in the future.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you our login page, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Additionally, we use Facebook Pixel and Google Analytics to customize content and advertising, to provide social media features and to analyze traffic to this site. Cookies from these companies my be placed on your site.

Facebook’s Privacy Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>  
Google’s Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Specifically, we embed YouTube videos into most of the articles on our website. If you are logged into YouTube, that will be recognized. You can see YouTube’s privacy policy here: <https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy_guidelines>

We also use Google AdSense for advertising on our site. You can check out how AdSense uses your data here: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics for all of our analytics tracking. You can find all of Google’s Privacy information here: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

We also anonymize all IP addresses before sending them to Google analytics in order to keep your data as anonymous as possible, and we use this data in order to better understand our site traffic and create better content for you.

Additionally, the WordPress plugin ‘Jetpack’ is used to gather view and unique visitor data on our site. This plugin is developed by Automattic Inc. You can view their privacy policy at <https://automattic.com/privacy/>

## Who we share your data with

We run Google Analytics and a Facebook Pixel on this site. Google Analytics is covered above, and the Facebook Pixel is used to help us advertise relevant products to you.

Additionally, we use Google AdSense for advertising on our site. You can check out how AdSense uses your data here: https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information. If you need assistance doing this, just email hello@thebreakdown.xyz

We retain Google Analytics information for up to 72 months after you visit this site in order to help use determine long-term content trends. This information is encrypted and anonymized.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. We use Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel for data tracking, and we use Google AdSense for advertising on our website.

Google’s Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
Facebook’s Privacy Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>  
AdSense Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>

## Your contact information

Breakdown Media/CrysisTV LLC  
Hello@TheBreakdown.xyz

### What data breach procedures we have in place

If there is a data breach, we will notify you of what data has been breached within 72 hours of discovering the breach has occurred.

### What third parties we receive data from

We use Google AdSense for advertising on our site. You can check out how AdSense uses your data here: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>

Additionally, any advertisements you click on our site may send you to websites with additional privacy and cookie information.
